# Veniamin Ilmer

Software Engineer

(929) 427 – 2535 28-20 203<sup>rd</sup> St Bayside, NY vilmer88@gmail.com

### **Summary**

I am a Software Engineer with diverse technical experience encompassing developing and customizing Enterprise Systems and Applications.

I provide a wide breadth of technical and business knowledge including ITIL and ITSM business process and alignment, data scrubbing and analysis, as well as superior customer / client communication.

### Highlights

#### **Certification and Training**

- IPautomata Development Trainer
- ITIL / ITSM Certified
- BMC Remedy ARS (Action Request System)

#### Spoken Languages

- English
- Russian

#### Education

Rutgers University – Bachelors of Science Degree in Computer Science

### Professional Experience and Project Involvement

	,				
Revenue Man Rust PostgreSQL Microsoft SQL	Implemented a process to do data normalization and data reconciliation of physician and hospital billing statements. It reduced the total number of records from 2.6 billion to 700k rows by breaking down the data into several tables. The process improved how long it took to query information and the amount of time required to process orders.				
Java 1.8 GWT HTML5 / CSS3 Microsoft SQL	Built a GUI interface for operators to manually handle insurance company's non-standard Claims, Service Lines, and Remarks that couldn't be processed automatically. The included building a custom Date field and adding multiple shortcut keys for image manipulation. This interface reduced the amount time required to handle such events.				
Java 1.8 Drools Microsoft SQL	Built a rule based engine that modified Electronic Remittance Advice (ERA) 835 files automatically. This engine allowed management to customize Adjustment Reason Codes, TransactionSet Dates, Remittance Payees, and other segments, specific for each provider.				
Java 1.8 Apache Derby Microsoft SQL RESTful API	Modified applications to pre-cache active data into a temporary database for faster user access. This process significantly reduced the load on the main database, while allowing multiple users work on the claims' data elements without affecting the primary system's performance.				
.NET C# Core 2.2 Looper Microsoft SQL PostgreSQL	Built a GUI interface with encrypted and permissioned login that allowed administrators to view reports and run superuser actions including add new clients and domains, make restricted database updates, and settling conflicting claims.				
Ansible Bash Shell	Built scripts that connected to hundreds of machines, stopped services, deployed new code, and started services again. This significantly sped up deployment time for all load balanced servers.				

Tinker Air For	ce Base Computer Scientist August 2018 – February 2019				
Powershell	Built a license-monitor engine for IBM DOORS database, which informed subscribers when a license was available. This software maximized the team's license utilization.				
Powershell BMC Remedy	Built a network drive access monitor, which automatically generated tickets to fix network connectivity issues. This monitor also logged events and generated monthly reports of issues and utilizations for management review.				
IPsoft Inc	Automation Scripting Engineer July 2014 – August 2018				
IPcenter Shell Rhino Javascript MySQL	Designed and implemented a tool which copied automata between servers, by recursively building all objects, and rerouting all links to point to the new automata. The tool became the company's standard way to deploy automata from development to production servers.				
Java 1.6 MySQL	Designed and implemented a tool which compared staged and deployed automata to find all changes made by a developer. This tool became extensively used by the QA team to detect updates.				
IPautomata IPmon IPwin	Designed and built a universal library / wrapper for handling patching of Unix, Windows, and Network devices. This service unified connectivity with external devices and standardized ticket verbiage. The new process increased the rate of automatic issue resolution by 48%.				
IPautomata IPcmdb	Designed and implemented the Collision Detection Service which reported potentially conflicting servers, networks and applications during scheduled and unscheduled down-times. This engine recursively looped through all child CIs checking for potentially affected systems and conflicts.				
Java 1.6 RESTful API	Designed, built, and deployed a system that granted and revoked admin access, for authorized users during scheduled release cycles. The system also ran security validation processes and removed unauthorized configuration changes on the accessed servers.				
Java 1.6 Rhino javascript IPwin Powershell Bash Shell	Designed, built, and deployed a Windows and Linux Patching system that included automatic scheduling and deploying security patches to multiple remote company networks. This system provided notifications as well as an ability for users to modify upcoming scheduled patches. The system has enhanced error handling processes, retry mechanisms, and the ability to generate incident tickets in case there is no automatic resolution.				
Python Bash Shell	Designed, implemented, and deployed a client-server service for managing customer's servers remotely using IPremote protocol as an alternative to SSH.				
IPcenter Shell	Trained and tutored senior developers how to use advanced IPcenter functionality, building custom functions that did bulk operations using backend Java functions.				
Column Tech	nologies Solutions Engineer Consultant January 2012 – June 2014				
BMC Remedy ITIL / ITSM SOP	Provided consultant services onsite with numerous clients, including Temple University and New York Life. Lead technical discussions, requirement gathering and development processes as well as training and UAT sessions with the customer going over differences between Incident Management, Change Management, Problem Management, and Service Request Management.				
Remedy ARS	Built a "Document Management System", which allowed employees to sharing files privately.				
Midtier	Optimized midtier to utilize memory more effectively by increasing the number of cached objects.				
BMC Remedy Midtier HTTPS Remedy CMDB	Upgraded BMC Remedy Action Request ITSM system, Atrium CMDB, and web tier to version 8.1. Configured HTTPS SSL on midtier; applied BMC Performance Security. Created CMDB asset data normalization and reconciliation jobs.				
Splunk Remedy API	Programmed integration between Remedy and Splunk to search and upload Splunk data into Remedy using Splunk and Remedy APIs.				
Bourne Shell Oracle	Implemented a script for copying environment configurations from the existing system to the new hardware building the new BMC system. This script has streamlined the installation process.				

Tablet Incorporated		Python Software Engineer	November 2010 – December 2011		
Python	Built a coupon discounter, which allowed users to make payments for hotels using coupons. This included an administration tool for managing coupon codes, managing the interaction between coupons, store credit, and credit cards.				
Python	Built a templating system, which streamlined the creation of marketing newsletters, by providing variables for user's names, emails, and other personal information.				
Python Bash Shell RESTful API	Built an API used by external Hotel Availability Systems that provided real-time data listing the company's current hotel reservations. This improve web performance by reducing the scraper traffic load.				
Groupable		PHP Software Engineer	July 2010 – November 2010		
PHP AI	Developed software that iterated through thousands of photos, and integrated with Face.com to count how many unique people are there in a facebook group. This software used the outlined results to provide targeted advertising.				
PHP AWS	Integrated with Amazon Cloud Servers to offload large amounts of data for third party storage. This significantly improved the website loading speed.				
PHP jQuery	Built an interactive search engine that allowed users to search for groups in specific locations. The search was able to parse and recognize zip codes, cities, states, and countries. If more than one result was found, a map view showed the locations of each group. The map was interactive and allowed users to zoom in and view details for each group.				

## **University Experience**

Rutgers University		Computer Science Student	September 2006 – June 2010		
Java OpenMoko	Built a decentralized phone app that allowed users to share their locations with each other. The app encrypted communication and sent GPS coordinates between users. Users were able to see each other pinpointed on a map.				
PHP MySQL	Built a web platform that allows users to create custom ecommerce stores. Users can upload a photo of products, set descriptions and prices, and then customize how their products appear on their webpage. When viewing an item, a "recommended products" section will appear with products that are similar to the one viewed.				
Python MySQL	Backtested various technical stock analysis methods (RSI, MACD, CCI, ROC, etc) with historical stock data to show that long term investing strategies usually outperform short term trading.				
Old Bridge School District		Administration Support	Summers of 2005 and 2006		
Hardware	Built new desktop computers from components include hard drives, CPUs, and motherboards.				
Ghost	Copied images of the Windows operating system from one master server onto multiple newly built computers.				
Visual Basic		utotyper, which was used to set network an saved administrators time when installing r	-		